{
  "LANGHINDI": 18,
  "qu1": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>The maximum length of the cable (in km) for transmitting data at a rate of 10 Mbps in an ethernet<br />\r\nLAN with frames of size 288 bits and the speed of propagation is 200 m/\u03bcsec __________. (Upto one decimal place)</p>",
      "OPT1": "2.8",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "Eq/4SLofJMP2fL3mgcaBVg==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "Eq/4SLofJMP2fL3mgcaBVg==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "2",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "Alphanumeric",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.00",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu2": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>MAC address which is internally assigned to computer supports</p>",
      "OPT1": "Flat structure",
      "OPT2": "Hierarchical structure",
      "OPT3": "Prefix and suffix structure",
      "OPT4": "None of these",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "Dsdj/LJX8pBs6q+b96fwiQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "Dsdj/LJX8pBs6q+b96fwiQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.33",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu3": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>Buffer is required at receiver side of data link layer. What is its purpose?</p>",
      "OPT1": "To accept out of order data frames and hold it temporarily for sorting.",
      "OPT2": "To discard out of order frames.",
      "OPT3": "To retransmit the data.",
      "OPT4": "None of these",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "Dsdj/LJX8pBs6q+b96fwiQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "Dsdj/LJX8pBs6q+b96fwiQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "2.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.66",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu4": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>The number of links used in half duplex in point to point link</p>",
      "OPT1": "1",
      "OPT2": "2",
      "OPT3": "3",
      "OPT4": "None of these",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "Dsdj/LJX8pBs6q+b96fwiQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "Dsdj/LJX8pBs6q+b96fwiQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.33",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu5": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>Consider the following statements:<br />\r\n<em>S</em><sub>1</sub> : DNS can use either of TCP or UDP, for its query and response messages.<br />\r\n<em>S</em><sub>2</sub> : SMTP is not used for transferring e-mail messages from the recipients\u2019s mail server to the recipients\u2019s personal computer.<br />\r\n<em>S</em><sub>3</sub> : HTTP can use multiple TCP connections between the same client and the server.<br />\r\n<em>S</em><sub>4</sub> : POP protocol is used to download an E-mail from mailbox server to a mail client.<br />\r\nWhich of the above statement are correct?</p>",
      "OPT1": "Only <em>S</em><sub>3</sub> and <em>S</em><sub>4</sub>",
      "OPT2": "Only <em>S</em><sub>1</sub>, <em>S</em><sub>2</sub> and <em>S</em><sub>4</sub>",
      "OPT3": "Only <em>S</em><sub>1</sub>, <em>S</em><sub>3</sub> and <em>S</em><sub>2</sub>",
      "OPT4": "Only <em>S</em><sub>2</sub>, <em>S</em><sub>3</sub> and <em>S</em><sub>4</sub>",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "Wkw/v0ACIC+JhZVbmq0HcA==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "Wkw/v0ACIC+JhZVbmq0HcA==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "2.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.66",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu6": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>In P-persistent CSMA network there are 6 systems in a slot. The probability of each station sending the data is 0.7 and to avoid collision only 2 stations should transmit the data at a time. What is the probability that channel is collision free? ________ (Upto three decimal places)</p>",
      "OPT1": "0.069",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "toTy/XgkPHviWUWS5Rc4zQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "toTy/XgkPHviWUWS5Rc4zQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "2",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "Alphanumeric",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.00",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu7": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>Consider different activities related to e-mail. Which of the following statements is/are correct?</p>",
      "OPT1": "Sending an e-mail from a mail client to a mail server uses SMTP protocol.",
      "OPT2": "Sending an e-mail from a mail client to a mail server uses POP protocol.",
      "OPT3": "Downloading an e-mail from mailbox server to a mail client uses POP protocol.",
      "OPT4": "Downloading an e-mail from mailbox server to a mail client uses SMTP protocol.",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "kANto1cr89QZ3IzSaugRPA==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "kANto1cr89QZ3IzSaugRPA==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "5",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "2.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.00",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu8": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>Consider a 40 Kbps satellite link has a propagation delay of 504 ms. The transmitter employs the \u201cgo back n ARQ\u201d scheme with n set to 15. Assuming that each frame is 105 bytes long, the maximum data rate possible is ________ (in kbps). (Upto two decimal places)</p>",
      "OPT1": "12.24",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "oJ9jSljs2Kk/fcwz/OS/gg==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "oJ9jSljs2Kk/fcwz/OS/gg==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "2",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "Alphanumeric",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "2.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.00",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu9": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>Match the following control commands and their respective port numbers:</p>\r\n\r\n<div>\u00a0</div>\r\n\r\n<div><img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAdEAAAEBCAYAAAAn/Z+0AAAgAElEQVR4Xu2dfXxU1Z3/P+vLtW4WaWwtjdRiXU3zYi3YRqiorKQQXRGBCAIGwQSI+JBInoRQIE9MUJM0T5CAYoBEAghIDAKCGtjoRqUF0yK1NBtZFAq/KbXK0jR1qWZ/5965d+bOZCbzkHtn7iSf+xdMzj3ne97n3Pu555zvOd9/+D9xgRcJkAAJkAAJkIDfBP4h3EW029qG1997G6+tWI1DXdr6j0RiQRJuG3kH7ouNwmV+ozHDDZ+hZcV0LEIhWoviMNgMJtEGEhiABPrNe6a7HfUPTIPlmNPL0t6iEfFZqMxJwvhovm187eZhLKIX0dFUhoyMl9A+/GHkioafHheNQXLNL8Ha9jpeXluBt8eux67kmLAU0e6OOky/uxDHcSdy36pFUvSVvrYr05EACehCoD++Z75ER10KJha8C9ySj/2vJiMap7E7dRay91sdv4XnyEOXVvcnkzAV0Us415SDezOa0DU8Czt2piJ2kGuLd+Niyyos+GQmtoeliEodfQkytrei/cT/YkRBY9h+DPjTIZmWBMxDoL++Z6R3YyHGJr+ELlVEL9P8FvEIag/nI24wVdSXvhieImqfkrgGiXW7YIm7xpe6hleaiy3InfffeGDpX5E7oxzt7Njh1X60NvwJ9Nv3TO8iiokVOFCTgKHUUJ/6cFiKaODTnGJqpuUQ3vuPs7j+sX/Dp3lPoUme7o1GV8c72FVfAUvDhzZwEfFIe+YJPDQlFlFyZ5KmiA/h/bcP4thPclAgCXe3FW373sY7r3+CHxcvVr7cbOl++eExnIq8HTccLUO2nKdYo7WsQOrDo5X8emsfqZOXIvdCIiqm/A2b5TWMfvzB4FNXZSISCC6BgN8znR1oaf5PtJz6Fyy87w8oeOAA7twtLcdcgU5v7xk37xR1Pfb1Yz/Bc4WKb4Sc7j0cP3oWkfd/D0fzcrHthFjnFEtbBavSMLtXP5CeInrj+fdRsyILLyIJG4vmY1TUFcGFHcalhaGIajqAH2uFjgdCEsg4JE75HNte/lieJt15zwksis9E6x0W7KycjZgIK1oKn0BK/XncU7kdq28+hBny2qR0DROj351YjBrbdIgsuMr0B95B7ph52Cb/GIXxWeVYmXY7hpw/iJXzFqHhhI9CKH0Bz9iB6zctF8L8lWPq2j71EsY9jqaTQFgQCOQ9o1lrlL/DZ2HS2T3YeeInsk/D3H8+gDSP75k6pF+wYJK0Tml/p6QCJTOQ0nDa9tOcTcLB8C6Il5Pm3ROP9HoLUkd/C+fFh/eC5FofZq20dVMbIwIxc7KxcNRN+Nf4sYjusTwWFo0WEiPDUETFALAXhxsnsbR1Pcd6ojRFKotcLNIaNyDjx5fQ8YlI8k6WWGT/tWbd0c10B1SvNtsDITn52MvSTrW6nQJyPFy2B6F3T9vujgak7Y1BSeZom6OU3W46GIXkKWGhA5JAYO+ZaHSqIqf4a/y48xN8MigKX7+y0Ot75saTijOh/YPZ/bvD93ePu6ZzN517Ee11OZhRcKAXP5MB2Q28VjosRRR2oYIHhxt3ncSTGNm2kaQ0fOaUl72T2r3X+iKiqj2v4MaCV1A/shmJ08Q6p715FFGPjRS/XEBbxQLMrGpz23i+iLDXVmcCEiAB7wQCes94ePfAt/dMn0TUXsb3xYf+ekz/ywbMcvueGezGsUj7fpRm2/qpr4n3Vvc7RXiKqFiftHvnRtyL3FeLkRSj3dfkj4iqX3rakahjtHtSHTnaH6i+jEThfauKGHUWLL+AhVXOC/uOL88ElDUXY+pQrln43dt5Awn4RSCQ94wnEfXtPTNInWXry0hULDbJ21Y8OgZ5ez9SRP3pJmEqovIcp2OfqJMTULdYvD+I2uI8VDe77HnyMC3afa5JXqt48/oU1G4SDkJRXcpoELZpX2mEaBfRwfI6aXVCFKzqNhu307lATNJqbMifoKyJrsXXjz2DnIQYZS+ru2aSHrQnsARL3WxncXzJxqTXYbs61etPazMtCZCAnwT8fc94ElHxCvHhPdPjYznKat+/qZ2Fckw1j8ScunXIE46O8ppo8SUsXJ2Nqb0elqD5OLDPtFlxtDoX88ubQe9c/7pIGIuoVFFJMFtx8PgH2Od0YpFw6knPwKSbonHbJJt3bc+1Uu3Xlovwipwj4hfB8mQiJtu93ITX7ZGNyEsqFicjSYvwy1EYfxGrkosVhyNlvfLGT5UTQb6BmOFXiT2ewilg+CMo89qxVZHUOhGonnhuThmhk5F/PZ2pSSBgAr6+Z5wdi+TinLam+fCeEV63qph1yR792Zjw9/VIWak4HCnPvX3aN+ImxHzvHNo7xEf7nFWoXDrFq1NQz3ehAqbHjoSAgQ2oG8NcRE3YVv12b5kJWdMkEhigBNw6Fg1QFqGuNkVU7xagiOpNlPmRAAm4EKCImqdLUET1bguKqN5EmR8JkABF1LR9gCKqZ9PYHZfUTDV7VPUsh3mRAAkMUALuDkrg/vFQdgaKaCjps2wSIAESIIGwJkARDevmo/EkQAIkQAKhJEARDSV9lk0CJEACJBDWBCiiYd18NJ4ESIAESCCUBCiioaTPskmABEiABMKaAEU0rJuPxpMACZAACYSSAEU0lPRZNgmQAAmQQFgToIiGdfPReBIgARIggVASMFBEbQeqL0Kh1yDU/gH4A3anTEF28xea2yaj7HA5pkZdLn7z8Pdd/4Z905fgUK+FDcP4+CE41Hy0d5Oufhxly84ie/Eet+ki4nOwsWg+RkXZwpV1W9uwZ9s65FY1o0v+xRZF/olp9+E++wH3/lFgahIYmAREIIi2Q/jl6S/RfWof8lvuxK5ew37pQKmzAy1v7sXWFacw6ZD6ntHk29vfxd8OvViCDOXZj4jPQmVOEsb3GmVFB5uZRdAIGCaivUWF73vtHKd2XJG+C4czYyHJp+Ny83drExauAFbWJiBKJPyqrQJjpm1GbOVrWJ9wnfhFEv3HsNX6z8D9zyi/dYqQaDNFgOybHCItnUr077/GA/+Zidgu8e8x87DtG4uw44j4v2SEGoVh/3exZFUaZv/wDFbPeAxv3fo0LGkPIlYSVpGmbUs1cl+5CZVGvwD6Dps5kIA5CEixdnN+jVtm3YfbsBX3Jr+ELsOiGUli3Yw3Gl9AmXU4Jp3dg52fPojaw/mIGywF6vT2d+ldcFoOY5b791TsrJyN6M7/wMp5i9CAx7FjZypiB3kM+GkO3rTCJwIGiagUEmgJMra3ilBg/4sRBY1u4mP6ZJ/HRDYRXA24FVFVJDV/FyKavm0YyhTB7SmikmA+h7f/D/iHuKUihuggUbYbEf2qDZWZp/HQGiHG0r9HT0f1sHznILj235eh9pHjSMmGZqSsVEmbT99Q8G4SGGAEPMfs1A+EJJJv4/dX3Ya46Iu22a8P5jo+lmUR7e3vavjFTfhR3S5YRLxPKXTjxZZCjE1uwVT7b/pZzJxCQ8AYEZVGa/P+Gw8s/StyZ5Sj3Smmnj4V9VtEXYrtKaLu7HIjotpkqljeWoFWZYQr/1n5feOkGmy8aSseKvibI7i3PtVnLiQwgAkEQ0S1eJUlIicR9fZ3NbYokPtWLZKir5RvUGfoznj4+B/AjRq2VTdARKUOXorcC4momPI3bH5gGizHrkGizl9ephVRdTr3+cuR/eqzmP7XzZg1TXxIiElkOVD4Dd+wdZbImzEhLhrSeJcXCZCAPwTCQUQ9fIBLy0pjMtFGEfWnwU2dVn8RlUKBzdiB6zctF2sHX+FcUw7uzWjSfe1CFdELXvBG9jrdq10T7ctItAz75hzDDGmNRnYaWozFSdPENNBgkanqCHEOR18ow7YTNtci+RqegtpNixGnOCCZuqfQOBIwDQGKqGmagoZAdxHt7mhA2t4YlGSOto2y7OHB9A3XY9qRqE+d6iLa63Iwo+Ad3GjAerFPJjARCYQtAYpo2DZdPzRcZxG9IJxzFghv1ja3qCLmbNJtu0t4i6jj42L/o+68i/thT2OVSEA3AuEkot9ysya6Gt+x7wrQDQozChEBfUVUckFffgELqxIwVOO9bd/uEpGAsuZiTB1q2z/Zl8tUIurqnaup2FdtNcg+PRVV8jYax2VjsgfjGjcIT+DIvqDgvSQwwAiEg4i688RVfzuJbI2z0QBrvH5XXR1FVPJGewJLsNTNdhbbwQspDZ8hJr0O29Wp3s4jqJyRjGq/900FsE/UWcIUV/NXvEynqnZ/3+lr0p6V6p0rjpSw7xN1KucrWJsWY8HRWzRrpN3o7DiI2uIivPW9PGzIn4Aobhfrdw8WK2QkAdXz9V2gxz5RdTYM+nnES34ekoNkh3afqPaL2MPf7e+32Tbfh0EdqM9IQdk/5uBAjfNAw0hazNtYAjqJqCo2p2VrnaZt1Q54TONQo3b8rkBENMATi3o70ehqNyKoeNFpTzhyOClJ4piFsRnaE4uGi4d2h7K/VNNo9tNMVuOQgiAiXpzjNOd+3E3vXGN7N3PvZwQ0I1DXmtnFVE8RdfeuEQXb3xfe/i6dq/I+alZkoarZKm6UPPRXYvGjExDNgxb6Td/USUT7DQ9WhARIgARIgAR8JkAR9RkVE5IACZAACZCAMwGKKHsECZAACZAACQRIgCIaIDjeRgIkQAIkQAIUUfYBEiABEiABEgiQAEU0QHC8jQRIgARIgAQoouwDJEACJEACJBAgAYpogOB4GwmQAAmQAAlQRNkHSIAESIAESCBAAhTRAMHxNhIgARIgARKgiLIPkAAJkAAJkECABPQRUXfn42oMiojPQmVOEsbLQar7enk4r1LOVpxNmVWOlWm3aw51l4JiN+ONxhdgafjQUXhEPNKK5mLSPWPFOZbdbs7C1SbNwcai+RjF4Nl9bTzeTwJ9JHARHQfrUfpUue0sauk5XrMEKROibfGLDbtEuU1lyCiMhOVIJmIvdy3I3d9dbMVIJFpWIPXh0Qw6YVg7BT9jfURUtttNZAWcxu7UWcjeLw5f7hFtoS+VdR/FxXbY81IciHoMlrQHETtEHIxf+ARSfjUCuULEp6sHvndb0fbaNjy/TBwKj3uR+2oxkmKEwKsBxL+hOZBepD1anYv5+7+LJavSMDs2Cgy60pe2470kECgB6blfhaTmEShZOgXREeKDWn6/APdUbkd1wjCDnk0ReUmENJw1rRzt7oJVwP3fpXCHs4q/RI70Aa6+i+rPG2xroGx5X6AEdBRRdzH+NL9FPILaw/mIG6yPBNniidbi+wWNTqHXHL/XYvkXv8BDLw7zGMO0+1wT0uIz8eb1WdixMxWxV/4GlaOno9o1Pqga8qyXuKGBNgDvIwES8JWA9KG+BC/9IA+WuGvETUGKKyqFNMtYj9+dfQ+HrCk9wx66/bsU6akANZEZiq3CWjmGcCHOpO/C4cxY9BjM+oqB6UxFIGgiiokVusbQs4nlZsS6RIi3/d6EieWPAyuK8NslziLrTF8dPZ9BYt0uWMaetonorRVorU0Qk8PKpYjoxkmb0FoUBz0mpU3VC2gMCYQFATGzlF8HZGcpH+PBEFEptNoqvDNuLm5Ym4zsD+a6iKi3vzvA2kR0D8Y1bhAhEyPDgjiN9E7AUBG98bwtlt6LSNJ9TdGdiKqx+15EKrbNsSIpeQ8mSuIof7W6v2wduxSQRrRz/orVriKqTuc+fzmy1Wlf71yZggRIwHAC6kfwScOmSLs7GpC2NwYlmdfiYMqUHiLq7e92BJ0fiYDcz+LUnBLkxQ01aNrZcOAswA0BY0TUXlAEYuZkY+Gom/Cv8ZIDjz5TuVL2DhGtxeyjmUhpkAKCi4X7gkw88uAduKr5aRE0+5hthNmLiIo5Fywck4k2aYrlKaBaFtEy7JtzDDOSX0IXpDosxuKkaYjTxTGK/ZAESEAXAtI06ozH8NZPS7Ehf4L+zjrdwqcjfT3w8zxMHXoeu11F1NvfpUr2cLqkc5EubW+iTIwRUbsT0UW01+VgRsEBdA1X1h11ElJP07kqW09rpq7sbSPR1fiONC18/3n307kmajCaQgIkIInTOdlpcNHZGdhZORsxOr1XHGxtTkwLPpmJ7ckxYuSo7AqwT+d6+7ubVupsx+7nliC74WOMcPHlYJuGLwGDRVSAUT1eu4Z5HxX6wdGbiNrLjc7H/leTEe12EHwJ55pycO8ywNJcjKlDfksR9aMNmJQEQkNA+jhfgaWnpmKdESNQtyNI55pGpubisdYyFB+T9tn0vCI9OA/RuSg0PcbIUsNcRHt65zpgSQv+CzCz6hzGF9SiPPnmnvvI5Omgp/Ffj222ucfTC9fIvsa8SUAHApKAWlB1cRrynPaD65B1r1m4jkRdE7v+3dUJypbe9vHfijl0LjK6wYKWv44iqozqMprQpU7nQtljWd4Mh3euuqfqeSC9DtszRwe0SdrWGVeLPHpxF5cX81PEKBMYn56DxxPvQ6x8YIJ0AMMrqFn+Av448TnH4QyqiEKzTzRoTcGCSIAEeiegWR7qkVCd6bpc+XgG0vQUKnVts+NB91v1evz9ktiOk4LprWPtTpU2x0cLjo8tdf9Rz+YPSwK6iag6TXHcFYN0osgzT+ChKbHKwn9fRdTNiUVuN0ArhkgHK+x7Ha+uLcO2E+rUizjZKD0DU8aNw33y4QnSnq4s4Yi0R2P9cPEQ7hCu6MaegxKWvYZGk0AICHh8x8i2GCWi7k9Ic0zXev77e4lf4Jl5i9CgvHci4hfB8mQiJvPAlhD0HuOK1E1EjTOROZMACZAACZCAOQlQRM3ZLrSKBEiABEggDAhQRMOgkWgiCZAACZCAOQlQRM3ZLrSKBEiABEggDAhQRMOgkWgiCZAACZCAOQlQRM3ZLrSKBEiABEggDAhQRMOgkWgiCZAACZCAOQlQRM3ZLrSKBEiABEggDAhQRMOgkWgiCZAACZCAOQlQRM3ZLrSKBEiABEggDAhQRMOgkWgiCZAACZCAOQlQRM3ZLgZbJR3A34w3Gt8BkgqQFH2lweUxexIgARLonwQMENGL6Gg5hPeaN8HS8KGGmojoXpCEUT8YgQlx0QFFbrFl5v7AZ23zRKaXYOlHz2Jp8xe9tlrv6cQh9Vnljggv/ab9tfwmo+xwOaZGXd5vaseK9HMCUkCJ17bh+WWrcUiKJyEFuFizBCkT+vJO8cRMvMsO1qP0qXJbWZACV6zE4kcnIFobBLyzAy1v7sXWFacw6RCfp37eA3tUT18RtYceGyIEMxOPPHiX0tlE5JaOd7Crfg2abnoGu+RI8X25pKjyhRib/BKucAqFJmL4rXgEW0ctw6S9u4GiZ20CoYY4u7UCrbUJ4lGw3T/x11PxduaP0eUmL1vYoqU4EPUYLGkPKiHU+mJzH+6VXhxbqpH79ihskO3v66VGrQFFtK8oeX9wCVx8B5Vln2PS4imIjrCipfAJpNRfrm/YM6VGctSYRWeRvmkx4sRDZ20pxYLkWpyZWIEDNffhst9IszkvoMw6HJPO7sHOTz2ESQsuIZYWZAL6iWj3aexOnYXs/cA9ldttQa6dKiMJ1yos+GQmtvdZRNXgtpsRW/ka1idcp3Z7Idbv4yi+if9Z/Ta+X5GKWGmQ1UNEpZ9qkH16KqrEvbbYpD0DfHv6Pcht5Nb+vtlAEe0bP94dKgLdHW/hdfwb7peXINSP6VdwY0GjDh/n2lpJeYvZrAtJWGt/v0gf6dOR0nCL+Ph8Dredexe/v+o2xEVfxO6UKcj+YC52HMm0vXN4DRgCOomoY2RoD8jdt6Gm1wawCZyriHq4zY2IalN6ysv2exMm1u2CJe4arzYZlsCL/f6XSxH1nxnvMB8B9b3zW8zXMwC3x4p2ioDfMzGz6iaXGRxliYQiar4uEgSLdBJR9QvtNCLmbEJrURwGG2x8T+HTTtHGwuljMAARtU3nZuFFpGJn5WzEaNdAXEbYnR2teGvvZuRXNUNeOhmeglp5CuhyZRq7wrE+7LSGozr4bMa7NyVh0sfrkC2vI2vWXnASh14sQYaat5R/vDQtPR5/aXkD+xreBO7/Gf78wipss08ndYp16Ua8VFxqD0QeEZ+FypwkjI+WWoYianD3ZPZBIGB7Rmtw/v5c5CTE9MHPwldjlffc8XnY/2oyou0DBYqorwT7Y7owF9HVuODUKhEY4W5ax2cRrcXso5liuua0yFVyhNKu67prfiGC0jrJk3/AzFeLkRQzSIjmayhetBs3ra7B9L9swKxpW/G9glqUJ9+MQZ3t2P3cEiGU58WUdzHi92ZgieL8FBGfg41F8zFqiHhQ5XWeC0hUR8Cu9qv/l/2mIhCTXoftjwK1SYdx1/a5wJoFmPniEOQ62bRciOw9KGsuxtShl8HalIWxGVwT7Y8Pdb+vU3c76h+YBssx+ZNVdi5Kr7cgdXRUH30teifXfa4JafGb8cOGDciIjdQkpoj2+z7XSwV1F1Hcku/ylWYMXvcjUdc1DKVsn0VUu77qg90XW5A7RnyVProLhzPV0a805VOBM4mP4pvVs5Di+tWq3LMtWuL0CL77juQgtQdjNGu7Perm1v4v0VGXgokFnwunih3ioR5kM1jOPxW/XaJdI3JdO7oR5ymiPjQwk5ibwEW01+VgRsEBdEU8gtrD+YgbbNA6kuzz8Tj23VZq+yB2AkMRNXc/MdY6nURUsyYakaCMdq4w1HJ365haZyGnwo0SUWsTFo7JRJuTh7CLcA9z/ahwfuBGfthzbdc3EVWnZD92ElGPzlBOto7EZxRRQ/snMw8SAfWjtOtO5L5Va9Ce5wviwzgTz1/9tBsBlepJEQ1Sa5uyGJ1EVNTN7p1rRYTsAp4AMWto2KW/Y1FP71yvxjuNKrVrJJoH671xzh8VylRU2Ygaee04wo2DVF9EVMzTysJ+2KUNZHf9uzfhR/IUcSSnc702LhOYjoB4dhqK/gvjV0x2vFt6fQb1qIE02rWgCsko6TECVfOniOpBOlzz0E9EJR1VnHGqmoWQxi+C5clETI5V1imkvY77DuDdr+9EasKN6BJbTGZNex6Q1vMyR/vpFOBpn6iHZvDyoNlEa7WwRTst61uTdlsPYuW8xThyax4ql4q9a4Mkp57jwKjbcO1/rRN1LMcZdb0zSkzBNpUhY9l5+xqqbb+ru+lcjairI2mnUa3qKQjn6VyxStxWIdZEq845Dovosq3F5lpnKE5Sl5SpYBj49e4bP6YiAd8JSI49C7B1yFLlEBRlOrcEyJbX/yWnObX/S8+F69ql7yXJKcU762h1IVZ9PR+be3tHqWu0Hdwn6ifhfpFcVxG1EXF/YpEkqoVTx+H2SbGIukwcvhCwiLo7scjTyTvqlOceTWMN14iOm7yuXuT3Xi/tx4PzCSqS9+0rqFkuPGdPyMerIGbOYixOmubYW6Y9VUn2ur0fkKdaFZvl3+4DlI3e7ZLn7vIkfHdtMbZpDmSK1H4AqIcz5G5Bu1xzrZPUOdueNnu5Wh79ok+zEv2WgHiejmxEXlKxcoKQ1K8fwwP3xmsOQ9FLRNV82tzTlJ/LUfil07OkJA3gHdJvm2wAVMwAER0A1FhFEiABEiABEhAEKKLsBiRAAiRAAiQQIAGKaIDgeBsJkAAJkAAJUETZB0iABEiABEggQAIU0QDB8TYSIAESIAESoIiyD5AACZAACZBAgAQoogGC420kQAIkQAIkQBFlHyABEiABEiCBAAlQRAMEx9tIgARIgARIgCLKPkACJEACJEACARKgiAYIrrfbuq1teP1AI+q/mIZt9hBpBhTELEmABEiABEJKQB8RdQ2S67ZK7s65DKTu7s7Odc4nMr0ESz8SsUW159K6Kar3dOKM2qxy5aBrX+1UD4U/Id/gdJ6tr1kwHQmQgA8ExPnbHa14a+9m5LfciV2vukZR8iELr0nEOeAH61H6VLlyVq94J6SvxOJHJ4hAE0qIqs4OHHqxBBlVzZBPx47PQmVOEsZHS4fh8xoIBPQRUZmUJqaoU2BuqbO/g131FbA0fCh62b3ItUdcCBSxpyguUpSHR7B11DJM2rsbKHoWU6MuB3rEE7XdP/HXU/F25o/RJUdSeQlXaA5xtx0qvxQHoh6DJe1BzQHX3m32PyqMelD9EYzaVGqzmRcJkIBnAp1HUDkjGdVSYAen941+0OTwgYvOIn3TYsRFAVYlCMQZNcwgpEDds5D791Q5OlJ053+IiE6L0IDHsWNnKmJVodXPJOZkQgJBEFG11pqoCDp0evfxRCXBfh9H8U38z+q38f0K0ZElPXITlFsbwNtTIGuPAa69NKT/96kj2JtQdricImrCB4UmmYmAEiT7z5E429CEdh3eJz1rJ31oi9msC0lYm3Cd8mfpI306UhpukZ/TyX9p0MTovUYzkGjBVDlur/Qbr/5OIIgiKsaqcmDoQhxH36PQ6x+UezNiK1/DevsDI2mvFGe0CRP9fCD8sk3uYRTR/v6gsX56EbCFUZz74vexJuMCnvp38T4xRETd2at9Tp/Bvx54HBMLnGPyqu+4MwHEJtaLEPMJLoGgiqj4tEPumHnY1jUMiX4KkyuWnkKlnaKNhdOEqJuRqDY/d6Knxgh9EbapmphepmYkR6I929YhV14XicJd8T/A0eZ2jLGLssuUthxXdLkyTSwCdTutu0iWKfFRB51CyytiTaZAiQs6/GEUrErDbDXQeXD7CksjgdAT6JamUJ/FhawKzMXLto/yoImoMhI9Pg/7X30Qf6maiZlVLrNH1iYsHJOJNopo6PtKkCwIcxFdLeLYa68IjChoxK7kGCjL/rY/+iyitZh9NFNM15wWN2kDWTvlpilQDS7eLEaxJchJiEGE9Qi2VhehoOEMxqsiKpU/50NM2io5P6j3lOOP9gfN3UhU+k28IO63ICn6SjFYVdaArCl+Bw0PUl9iMSRgMAHp2VmHrLd/ivLM0YhQZrZOztmE1qI4GO3K032uCWnxm/HDhg3IEOtEbRUUUYMbPCyyD5GIGjGd624NQ2kDn0XUed+04gEAACAASURBVDrXawuqXslYLL5MHd6BbqdzhRdfS/NH+OLUPuQrnnyIr0BrbYIYu3qazhXegS1v43eff4x9K1YrHoLKKJXOR16bhwn6GQHpeZtRi8g1qzB16OWyc6DkEIhgiKg8An4c+24rRXnyzRjk6ZnlSLSfdTrv1QmiiDo8aqF6t3ka4Hm3W1mvdF7H1DoLOWVhlIgq09P7H92Fw5r9oK4iavuCzcSb1z+M3MfuwR1x/4R9P5uJ6lt7EVH5oZ2F7P1DkFgwDxPu/CkG703pOX3kAysmIYH+QMDhU+GuNn3/MPfMSHFkuvppRUCllOqH77eQ+1atbbZIXDYbV+M7Lv4V/YE/6+CeQPBEVJ2O/PQuHba4qE4/PZ2B3FbTJxGtxffdTQX31nPUfIfl9zISvQYddSnODgg97Ok5ErU9jKWA3SY6H/EhJgEHAc1HuaEj0Ytor7OgCskokUeg6qWWr/XEVX87iWyNsLLV+jcBHUX0Es415eDejCZ0OS30S3sgX8fLa4tR/d6PkF5vQeroKMeapSqufu2t8rRP1ENjqQ5N0c5ip6b2f1+neqe6beec/WCGIeel/aVZqGq+qKzPXo+Tsoj+DWmNYi3lx1/iaHUu5pcLJ6Qe07mOr1pVRC+l12F75i1iSXQj8pKKxZQup3P79yPJ2vlGwJOIqs8kbM9bbKRv2blL1W0Vz2ohVn09H5vFGqxDQJXE9nfXbNRKe0kHdaA+IwVl/5iDAzUJGNqHmbbAjeadwSagm4j2OtUSEY+0oum4647xPQ8t8FtE3Z1Y5ElYvoK1KQtjM/ZouA4XD9cO8XBJj4SbvK5e5J/jjvygKaIoed0mrcYL93+IhBmK05PI7+U9I7H3UbEJW2wMj4jPwcaCW9A6eTaqvxAmKOX9+LODto3achoLdpbH4f+VpSKlXjqgIl58fCzB7a3peKhKOg1JW4dgdxmWRwKhJKA51MXJDNXjX3L4WSCWPfoqopp97e6qq3wAD5EPZZE+mq0ilZsTjUKJimUHhYBuIhoUa1kICZAACZAACZiIAEXURI1BU0iABEiABMKLAEU0vNqL1pIACZAACZiIAEXURI1BU0iABEiABMKLAEU0vNqL1pIACZAACZiIAEXURI1BU0iABEiABMKLAEU0vNqL1pIACZAACZiIAEXURI1BU0iABEiABMKLAEU0vNqL1pIACZAACZiIAEXURI1BU0iABEiABMKLAEU0vNqL1pIACZAACZiIQPiJqDirtm3fezj+y18BSQX2EEQmYkpTSIAESIAEBggBA0RUCiR9CO81b4KlQRyebr9GiriYSRj1gxGYEBfdMyKCV+CuB08bGT/QqzFMQAIkQAIkQALQV0Q7P5JDAVmapUDSmXjkwbsQPUiKB9SNzo53sKt+DZpuega7kmMcodD8bARHtBiKqJ/omJwESIAESEBnAvqJaPdp7E6dhez9wD2V21GdMMxFKKWR5Cos+GQmtushohGPoPZwPuIGM2ifzn2C2ZEACZAACfhIQCcR1Uy1OgXk9tEKP5LZR6IUUT+oMSkJkAAJkIARBHQS0c/QsmI6UhpOI2LOJrQWxWGwV2vVKd4Kx9qpFLz7mSfw0JRYRNkHmJdgbXsFNctXYZsUsHr4cFx74gROuohot7UNe7atQ25VM7p6BMd1zkM2zS72avDdvgbx9VphJiABEiABEuhnBEImot3nmpAWn4nWOyzYWTkbMRFWtBQ+gZT6847p4O5ztt92/gvKmosxdeiXaK/LwYyCA+jSiKgtr+X4dMZqbMj/GQb9pgazppXjjCLogzrqMP3uTfhR3S5Y4q4RS7TtqE8/gjuq5iD6MopoP+vTrA4JkAAJBI2A7iLqGOH1Vocv0VGXgokFv8aIgkbF0ajnlPCNJyXxK8RJzei253Tu58ooGEhURNI1zV1/fEnO57g8Qs3ApBsi8M2bxyEu2vt4OWgtwYJIgARIgATCjoBOIqoRwIgEZdR4RS8w1OnfzzQiKgaI8ohRiJ081foQ8JIktO86TRH3ENFBHah/YBosx7p6lqeOVgedR9uWauTmbkG7PRW9e8Out9JgEiABEjAZAZ1EVNTK7p1rRcTEChyoScBQj46z7kaiDhG1jTzvgpjLxdjklwCfRqLOguyRc2cHDr1Ygoyq93CjfRRsslahOSRAAiRAAmFBQD8RlXTU+j5qVmShqlkIafwiWJ5MxOTYKNtWF/mkoQN49+s7kZoQDShrom9en4LaTYsRF9WFtooFmFmlcfC52ILcMfOwDfci99ViJMUAHU1lyMh4Ce32NVGgs822BtouHJPS6y1IHS2VKZyJOqwYFH0dultKkXshERXythvh0CSln/PfWCivs7opNyyajkaSAAmQAAmEmoCuImqrjPsTiyRRLZw6DrdPUj1vJe/cg6gtzkO1EF3p6iG88iENr6F40XLhmQvEzFmM7FGfYU1GjVjflC51SvYy4cH7Ol5eW+w2L1iPYGt1EQqUE5Qi4rNQmZOE8fKaKB2LQt0JWT4JkAAJhCsBA0Q0XFHQbhIgARIgARLwjwBF1D9eTE0CJEACJEACdgIUUXYGEiABEiABEgiQAEU0QHC8jQRIgARIgAQoouwDJEACJEACJBAgAYpogOB4GwmQAAmQAAlQRNkHSIAESIAESCBAAhTRAMHxNhIgARIgARKgiLIPkAAJkAAJkECABCiiAYLjbSRAAiRAAiRAEWUfIAESIAESIIEACQw8EZUPtc8H1ioBugME59ttarSad90nFwfmp61ZgpQJ0RjkW4b6pxJRbVqa/xMHXygT5xNrwskNfxi5j92G64MSd9ULJ7nWEeLs5Gw8Me0+3KcGNdCfBnMkARIgAb8IDDAR1bys5ZilyYj2GK7NL469JrbHQNUcmH+uKQf3ZjShy/7blfoV6FNO4nD/9q3IeiAXh64XgikO5J8ep4q5FESgES8Vv42bVq9DUnSQbFOj9nS5xHqVhP6VepQWSPFgRWD1glqUJ98cug8Pn/gyEQmQwEAgMLBEtLsd9QuXYMd7H6Ld9UVtZGu7Ewf7b8OQWBeMUbFzBbvVUHTwFERdCpy+Ep8mlYReRGXTlRB2Usi7kH14GNlJmDcJkEA4EhhAItqNiy2rsOCTeOR88Qs8VNWGCE2wb0MbrzcR9ShiRlokCeR0pDT4GMjcSFO0eXsaiapppI+gB6bBcgwYwYDqwWoVlkMCJNALgQEkokI48tfgfx5bjsl/3YrpdxfiuD2wt8Fzuq7icOMFHK3OxfzngUftQcSD2E9DPAr2WFNvIgpV/E8H7wMoiM3CokiABMKPwIARUWldclb9D7ChKA6Du09jd+osZO+/GJwRjV0cNB0kqI47Lh2TIhp+TyotJgESMCWBASKikkNREfaNfBoZsZHy+trFlkKMTX4JXcFwMOoxwrrC4dTTFYu0xg2KXUHqI3Z7IoLzEeFrtXweiZpsGtrX+jEdCZBAvyMwMES08wgqZySjWruFw96UQXDscSsOoZya1JQ9sQIHahIw1OAZbZ+eHG8iqv49JOvIPtWAiUiABAYYgQEgotKosxS5FxJRkTAMDq1wbHeJMFpITCeiYiyueud2ReGeyu2odmIToqegVxG9gLaKBZhZdY5bXELUPCyWBEigJ4H+L6KyR+dzwC/c7He0v7SNnVJ1CJa6//EyWI9sRF5SMQ6FbFR1yWGDENLx6Tl4PPE+xEZdIfeSbmsbXj/wAb6+cy6mBmmfaE9Otv2pki17tq1DbtVvMSarHCvTbkeUGUbOfKOQAAkMeAL9W0SdHHqcp20dByCofcCg9UH7tgzNaUBykT2FKyS90e2JRZJtGZgyblzwTgfyyEllFWR7QtIYLJQESCDcCPRvEQ231qC9JEACJEACYUWAIhpWzUVjSYAESIAEzESAImqm1qAtJEACJEACYUWAIhpWzUVjSYAESIAEzESAImqm1qAtJEACJEACYUWAIhpWzUVjSYAESIAEzESAImqm1qAtJEACJEACYUWAIhpWzUVjSYAESIAEzESAImqm1qAtJEACJEACYUWAIhpWzUVjSYAESIAEzESAImqm1qAtJEACJEACYUXAABEVB5u3VGDlJwmoTo7RRE1xw0U6LzW1CdfnZyJOOfg8rOjRWBIgARIggQFNQGcR7UZnWw1mLQcsO1MRO8hbqA1/0wfaVhfR0fIG9jWsx+/u34T1CdcFmlGA94l6dhxEbXEeqputch4R8VmozEnC+OjBAeapx22Cy8F6lD5VjkPy+fgjkWhZgdSHR5snSkpnO3Y/twSWb+fjcGYsLtej2syDBEiABHQioK+IysGvl+HPOdtgibvGNxO7T2N36lys/+EvsD1zNAb5dpdPqWzhvBqxruQsYqd8jm0vX0Bi3S7fbfOpFB8SyRFKluFU5hrkxQ0FrAexct4iNHx6D8qaizF1qC38WLAvKZLNrOIvkVM0H6OGiEDdhU8gpf68eeKLQo0h2obI9F0U0WB3EJZHAiTglYCOIqoEud5+G3b4NApVbZOCZhdi7JMXYdFZUGQR/f1ViIu7AZ1NWRib8THSGncgI1ZPqfbKGKKCyM25gNR1CSIAmnQpdU7egzGVr4VgZCzZ8BWsTQWoicywf1So4eHOmEKwpFmKdchaexRnm1vwR1PY5ENbMwkJkMCAIqCfiCrxIMtG1KC1KA5+TVLKcT9T8dsljdjlbR01oOaRBCOEIurG5q/aKjBm2mbEhkxEexplE9E9GNe4QXxoRAZEWrebpFmNjF/hrpxr8fzd2WijiOqGlhmRAAnoR0A/EbU2YeGYlYCrKEhBn18R624FW9Au2T38YRSsSsPs2CiH05EakPk7q9Baq47W9KukbdRlJhFVR6Inkf1WLZKir9SzsoHl1fkR6jOexak5JfKUs7fV7MAK8fUuaVajCPtGPo2MoS2iX2VSRH1Fx3QkQAJBJaCbiLofWXWiraIQx++32IRCXjNNRrU1BTuOZCLW7iXyB+xOmYLsD+a6/K4XC5OJqIHrwH4TUz9gjsmeReIKvXNR97kmZD4L5FQlYOh56eOMIup3u/IGEiCBoBAwWESlOkiesW/jd59/jH0rViteoJNRdrgcU6NUFR1IInoJ55pyMGXvrdhSORsxXj2Yg9IPbIUonrDZDR9jRIFRU+ve6iMcnFasxKdJJbYPL3mGgyLqjRr/TgIkEBoCxoqoPOKahez9Q5BYMA8T7vwpBu9NwcyqmwaoiNq29MxdezWeM5uAKv0v1M5FavnH3T4Pw0PjGBaaZ5OlkgAJhAEB3UTUNmJYjj9pRjC2F2IpYP9Nmt6d6VlEkdeP10SFgLZvxZJKIL3UDCNQMeLLrwOysxA32LECapuWb8UcMzgXSQ8QR6Jh8BqhiSQwcAnoJ6JuvHNVEb2UXif2gN4ilkQ3Ii+pWEzpukznGu6dq2y/KTgTmn2iEKc4SXUv+jse3+LLIRTB6JA2JtNbx2KjtE9UnBjVbX0fNSssOD62FOXJN+u6ZzfQGqkj05NzNvnv9R1oobyPBEiABHwkoJ+ICqGQ1vruXTYYqw/n20Y33eeUDfwfSkf0IL1+CW5vTcdDVSeEeerUXIRh+0QdXrl7XHAEc1pQOZVpWrnNO7nH5bo+7GPL6ZCsWz304YTNqSgifhEsTyZistZzWodyAspCGYEecro5mO0WkNW8iQRIYIAR0FFEBblATiyC5EiSiNJvP6P7iUUDrC1ZXRIgARIggSAT0FdExUk8gZyda2ZHmyC3B4sjARIgARIIIwI6i6hUc0ZxCaP2p6kkQAIkQAJ9IGCAiPbBGt5KAiRAAiRAAmFEgCIaRo1FU0mABEiABMxFgCJqrvagNSRAAiRAAmFEgCIaRo1FU0mABEiABMxFgCJqrvagNSRAAiRAAmFEgCIaRo1FU0mABEiABMxFgCJqrvagNSRAAiRAAmFEwAAR1e4TvRYnWw7hvebteHdUKdYnXNcTjXTmbmoTrs/PRJw4v5UXCZAACZAACYQLAZ1FVHti0RScyXgA2c1fCBbDejn43d9TjgJBK8U0fQP7Gtbjd/dvci/mgWTr8z2ijh0HUVuch+pmq3xXRHwWKnOSMD56sM+5GJtQMGoqQ0ZhJCxOAdONLdVt7p0dOPRiCTKqmiGf6jv8YRSsSsNsM5zpGwIcLJIESMC8BPQV0R5n56rRUz7vPQ6kHHd0Ltb/8Be6np/bbW3D6wcasa7kLGKnfI5tL18ITRQXOcLNMpzKXIO8uKEivNdBrJy3CA2f3oOy5mJMHRrqEbjmkPyrF2FHSEVU6jOZKL34CFam3Y4h583GyrwPMy0jARIIPgEdRVQRzO23YcdONdzXVyIcZBbGZnzsJZhytyGRXGQR/f1ViIu7AZ0+2WFQA0ih3nIuIHVdAqLkIpT6Ju/BmMrXQjAydqmn9PGTIUbpZ9/DIWtKiEX0D9j9RD2+WfxzJc6pjx9iBjUdsyUBEiCB3gjoJ6Ju4ok6QpF5E1FhoqExRX0V8+B1Flvw682IDbmIXhCB0lfhnXFzccPaZGR/MDfEIuraBu4+zoLXTiyJBEiABIIjonL8x5WAkyhoxKuuEDc0FyG7QcQWxUgkVpYgJyHGEfhZEWHLd1ahtVYdsenVeGYTUXUkehLZb9UiKfpKvSrqdz7dHQ1I2xuDksxrcTBlislEVEwzt29F1pJPMfuFxXQ887t1eQMJkIDRBHQbibofWanitUc40uRgY9F8jBryOY5W52J++eeY37gBGbGRSh3FNJ5hL3GTiahBa8B+dxbJjvT1wM/zxLrseQP5+20ZujvqMP3uQhxXb6Vzkf8QeQcJkIDhBIIkoi7TuV+1oXL0dGwcU4EDNQkYeplUz4EiopdwrikHU/beii2VsxEzSK58CC5pNLwKCz6Zie3JMbjMUP59qZ7k2fwaihctx7YTP0FuiEfufakJ7yUBEuh/BEIjouoL+0+LsP/VZEQPGBG1ecGaIgi5On1+TN5E0uOKTN+Fw5mxuNwUfZ7ORaZoBhpBAiTQg4BuIirccMWa6HL8qaARu+SRjXR5mEZ160SkjESR10/XRG3re0sqgfTSUI5APT0FRs4E+PHkib5RUAZkFcbBsYO2Uzg/zcTMNydqPL/9yJNJSYAESMAgAvqJaK/euQcRM2cVKpdOQXSEFS2FT6H067m2/6vTmYZ656ojmTOh2ScKcYrTkY3IK/o7Ht+ibv8xqEUDzVYdmXY8iNrD+cr2kkAz68N9sh0L8e6E5+R9olGXKewWHsOdLxcjKcYsh1P0oY68lQRIoN8Q0E9EhVBIa333LhuM1faXsCReBXgJNwLbK8Walpg6dOsgYsw+UcdIeI9Lgw33sm9Vz/bVHGTgNtvJKDtcjqlRoZo4VUag8slSjit007nSsZGlWJBci3bZnCiMT8/B44n3IZbHQurZMZkXCZCADgR0FFFhTY8Ti3y18DO0rEhE6bef0fXEIl9LZzoSIAESIAESCISAviIqTuKRHGdmLQcs9lOLvJllImcbb6by7yRAAiRAAiSgIaCziEo5a6O4qA5GvTBnFBd2SBIgARIggTAlYICIhikJmk0CJEACJEACfhKgiPoJjMlJgARIgARIQCVAEWVfIAESIAESIIEACVBEAwTH20iABEiABEiAIso+QAIkQAIkQAIBEqCIBgiOt5EACZAACZAARZR9gARIgARIgAQCJGCAiPq4T5T7QwNsMt5GAiRAAiRgFgI6i6g/Jxb5kzZQXFIsyoOoLc5DdbNVziQiPguVOUkYHx2Kg8wvoqPlDexrWI/f3b8J6xOuC7RiOt0n7DlYj9KnynFIjog2EomWFUh9eLQ4+F2nIvqaTWc7dj+3BJZv55soNFtfK8X7SYAE+gsBfUXU37Nzu09jd+pcrP/hL4w5M1eOCLIMpzLXIC9uKGA9iJXzFqHh03tQ1lyMqUOvCEo7dlvb8PqBRqwrOYvYKZ9j28sXQhRNxrm63R11mFX8JXKK5mPUEHF+ceETSKk/j3sqt6M6YZgSzi4oiDwUckGEQFuAmVVtCN2B+KGsP8smARIwOwEdRVQJN7b9Nj9iPhoVvUXBLoVXy7mA1HUJIhaIdCnlJe/BmMrXgjYSlEX091chLu4GdDZlYWzGx0GMIuOpC0qxXgtQE5kBS9w1NjpCVKffXYgzpgjILc1UrEPW2qM429yCP5rCJrM/zrSPBEgg2AT0E1G38UR9qI6hcUR7lv9VWwXGTNuM2CCKqMMKD0HKfcAUjCQ2Ed2DcY0bkBEbGYwiPZchzWpk/Ap35VyL5+/ORhtFNLTtwdJJgATcEtBPRK1NWDhmJdBDnNR1wHJlXTICMUmrsSF/gm3dTQ0G/Z1VaK1VR4xGtZY6Ej2J7LdqkRR9pVEFecjXxCLa+RHqM57FqTkl8tR3aJdEpVmNIuwb+TQyhraIfpVJEQ1yT2VxJEACvhHQTUTdjvC6z8nrbIvOzsDOytmIGdSJjqYyZGy6AZWvJiNaflMrQaE/mIsdRzIRa2RsaqPXYL0yN6GIqh8xx2TPInGF3rmo+1wTMp8FcqoSMPS89HFGEfXatZiABEggJAQMFFF11HcE8xt3iOnBQbYKftWGyszTeGiNOuoMlohewrmmHEzZeyu2yIIeirGWCUVU2+0UT9jsho8xoqARu5J9CGWne7eVArSvxKdJJbaZAnmGgyKqO2ZmSAIkoAsBA0XUV8EIhoiaJfC3r0x0aduAMgm1c5Fa/nG31g83gUNWQFh5EwmQQD8loJuI2kYMy/En+whGHYm+ght7HdUoIoo8g9ZEhYC2b8WSSiC9NFQjULX3mElExYgvvw7IzkLcYMeo3DYt34o5ZnAukrBxJNpPXz2sFgn0DwL6iahb71zp9KJSLEj+lfCGLUFOQgwGdXag5SgwKi4a8gSvod65ovwjG5FX9Hc8viUVsSGZwtV2FGUbUMEZE+wTtdkyvXUsNkr7RKOuQLf1fdSssOD42FKUJ99sa58QX+rI9OScTWgtikMojsgIMQIWTwIkYGIC+okobGuO9y4bjNWH8zWjG0XIkorlU3GcTwwycp+ociLStHK0u22AySg7XI6pUUZ6MrmOQPe4WBLa6clu9fCJEzanooj4RbA8mYjJsVEh9s51jEAPORELLS8TP8c0jQRIIEQEdBRRUQN/TyyC5ESSiNJvP2PMiUUhgspiSYAESIAEBgYBfUVUnAjU2VaDWcsBy05v06dmcfYZGA3NWpIACZAACehPQGcRlQxkFBf9m4k5kgAJkAAJmJGAASJqxmrSJhIgARIgARLQnwBFVH+mzJEESIAESGCAEKCIDpCGZjVJgARIgAT0J0AR1Z8pcyQBEiABEhggBCiiA6ShWU0SIAESIAH9CVBE9WfKHEmABEiABAYIAYroAGloVpMESIAESEB/AhRR/ZkyRxIgARIggQFCwAAR9eGwhW4r2va9jlfr/ooHtj8lAnFLh6EXYMsPFiEvbmjoz20dII3PapIACZAACfSNgM4i6v3YP1uordW4INl99SLsOJIpRFT8Wz53txxYtU4E8I7sW63sdwt7Og6itjgP1c1W+VfnA/B1KsbnbC6io+UN7GtYj9/dvwnrE67z+U7jEwrbmsqQURgJi9omxhfqoQRhy8F6lD5VLgctAEYi0bICqQ+PRlQoYqmHjAMLJgESMDsBfUXU1wPov2pD5ejpqIZGRNUoMC/8C+q8nrvrI1Y5PNsynMpcI49woUYt+fQelDUXY+rQK3zMqG/Juq1teP1AI9aVnEXslM+x7eULJgiFpq2TJuKN9sOmb9UO+G4p/Nms4i+RI4VoGyKCFBQ+gZT687incjuqE4ZxpiJgsryRBEhAbwI6iqgSK3P7bdjhTQRVER2Wj/2vJiNaHV3IsUV/jj8/o9PLUsov5wJS1yUgSianBgrfgzGVrwVtJCiL6O+vQlzcDehsysLYjI+R1rhDjLjNELFTYJE+fjLE6PjsezhkTXHMDujd23zKTwpcXoCayAxY4q6xtZoQ1el3F+JM+i4czoxFMILX+WQqE5EACQx4AvqJqNug3B74qiJ6awVaa1WBk9JKodGmI+X4PGdx1bGZbNPJm0WQ8OCJqMN8SSDMJqIX0FaxCu+Mm4sb1iYj+4O5IRbRno1tE9E9GNe4Qcepfh07FbMiARIYsAT0E1FrExaOWQm4EyfJkei1bXh+2WpbYO6fxWPUL5vxzh2uIqqMZgu+ZVDAbHUkehLZb9UiKfrKIDe8+US0u6MBaXtjUJJ5LQ6mTDGfiHZ+hPqMZ3FqTgmdzoLcW1kcCZCAdwK6iajHEZ68TvoY3ro1D5VLpyA64jzatlQjN3cL2uNdRdRgkek+jd2pc7H+h78IURBwg+vnvb2dU0g80tcDP88T68PnsdtMIqrMbFiOyZ5F4qJzkb/Ny/QkQALGEzBYRNWRJZCrHfl5nM41UmQu4VxTDqbsvRVbKmcjZlAo3DyNrJ+/nUUala/Cgk9mYntyjHDW+YO5RFRbnc527H5uCbIbPsaIgkbsku3lRQIkQAKhJ2CwiCprnPsSnNfZgi6iNu/TuWuvxnMhE1CpsU0koj1Ges6dMdJkTjx0Lgr9y4IWkAAJ9CSgm4gKjxmxJrocf3IaKXQKp5WZmFn1LT9HotBxTVQIaPtWLKkE0ktDNQJVwZtIRHv0BbOMRMWHV34dkJ2FuMGO8aZtuaAVc+hcxPcYCZCAiQjoJ6JuvXMd+w/PxOdgo7zv73Mcrc7F/PJmdN3issVFd+9ccXrSkY3IK/o7Ht+SitiQTOFqW1ud3j5jsn2iwkZ1ZNrxIGoP5zsJWHD7q43R9Naxtv4SdQW6re+jZoUFx8eWojz5ZphkY1BwsbA0EiABUxLQT0TVwxKWDcZqp5ewImRJxbbTZ4anoPbF8fjN5Nmo/kJiMtyxZ1LXfaKaAwTcop+s42jXW9uqI9A9Lgk1dfeWhWF/V0agzXJj2K9QTud2q4dinLA5dGOulgAAAYZJREFUFUXEL4LlyURMjo3iWqhh/YAZkwAJBEJARxEVxft6YpFbS5XtJ8XX6HdiUSBEeA8JkAAJkAAJ+EhAXxEVJwJJDjyzlgMWb6cWuRooCfDDm3F1SRGSYgb7aD6TkQAJkAAJkEDoCOgsolJFfIji0qO+jOISui7AkkmABEiABAIlYICIBmoK7yMBEiABEiCB8CJAEQ2v9qK1JEACJEACJiJAETVRY9AUEiABEiCB8CJAEQ2v9qK1JEACJEACJiJAETVRY9AUEiABEiCB8CJAEQ2v9qK1JEACJEACJiJAETVRY9AUEiABEiCB8CJAEQ2v9qK1JEACJEACJiJAETVRY9AUEiABEiCB8CJAEQ2v9qK1JEACJEACJiJAETVRY9AUEiABEiCB8CJAEQ2v9qK1JEACJEACJiJAETVRY9AUEiABEiCB8CJAEQ2v9qK1JEACJEACJiJAETVRY9AUEiABEiCB8CJAEQ2v9qK1JEACJEACJiJAETVRY9AUEiABEiCB8CLw/wEMTiZHhobqGwAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\" /></div>\r\n\r\n<div>\u00a0</div>",
      "OPT1": "a",
      "OPT2": "b",
      "OPT3": "c",
      "OPT4": "d",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "9m/iwvJKC6coEJr5HJJczQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "9m/iwvJKC6coEJr5HJJczQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.33",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu10": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>Suppose station A connected to station B with a intermediate router. The number of times data link layer are visited from source to destination _________.</p>",
      "OPT1": "4",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "znhkQSpRhMmrD25WN956iw==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "znhkQSpRhMmrD25WN956iw==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "2",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "Alphanumeric",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.00",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu11": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>A bit stream 10011101 is transmitted using the standard CRC method. The generator polynomial is x<sup>3</sup> +1. Receiver receives the bit stream 10111101100. With respect to the above scenario, which of the following statements is correct?</p>",
      "OPT1": "There was no error in the received data hence receiver accept the data received.",
      "OPT2": "There was error in the received data, but the received bit stream is a multiple of 1001, hence error was not detected.",
      "OPT3": "There was an error in the third bit from the left. Dividing that the generator yields 100.",
      "OPT4": "None of these",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "9m/iwvJKC6coEJr5HJJczQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "9m/iwvJKC6coEJr5HJJczQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "2.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.66",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu12": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>Consider a network connecting two systems located 4000 kilometers apart. The bandwidth of the network is 64 Mbps. The propagation speed of the media is 2/3 of the speed of light in vacuum.<br />\r\nIt is needed to design selective repeat sliding window protocol for this network. The average packet size is of 8 Kb. The network is to be used to its full capacity.<br />\r\nAssume that processing delays at nodes are negligible. Then, the minimum size in bits of the sequence number field has to be _________.</p>",
      "OPT1": "10",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "68C2atikmzKyBPF06VNlGw==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "68C2atikmzKyBPF06VNlGw==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "2",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "Alphanumeric",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "2.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.00",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu13": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>Consider the following statements:<br />\r\n(a) Hidden terminals can be handled by using either of RTS or CTS control frame.<br />\r\n(b) RTS/CTS exchange helps in reducing collisions and leads to efficient use of channel resources.<br />\r\n(c) 802.11 frame has three address fields.<br />\r\n(d) By the help of 802.11 frame, we can come to known whether encryption is used on not.<br />\r\nWhich of the above statement is correct?</p>",
      "OPT1": "a",
      "OPT2": "b",
      "OPT3": "c",
      "OPT4": "d",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "Wkw/v0ACIC+JhZVbmq0HcA==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "Wkw/v0ACIC+JhZVbmq0HcA==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "2.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.66",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu14": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>Go back N ARQ protocol will fail between two end system on a condition where <em>m</em> is number of sequence bits, when</p>",
      "OPT1": "S.W.S. < 2<em><sup>m</sup></em>",
      "OPT2": "S.W.S. = 2<em><sup>m</sup></em>",
      "OPT3": "S.W.S. = <em>m</em>",
      "OPT4": "None of these",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "fhPK/WKkcuYMengj9uY6cg==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "fhPK/WKkcuYMengj9uY6cg==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.33",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu15": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>Protocol of networks are applied between</p>",
      "OPT1": "Sender\u2019s data link layer and receiver\u2019s network layer",
      "OPT2": "Sender\u2019s data link layer and receiver\u2019s data link layer",
      "OPT3": "Receiver\u2019s data link layer and receiver\u2019s network layer",
      "OPT4": "Sender\u2019s network layer and sender\u2019s data link layer",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "fhPK/WKkcuYMengj9uY6cg==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "fhPK/WKkcuYMengj9uY6cg==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "2.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.66",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu16": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>The maximum power of the CRC generator polynomial is \u2018<em>n</em>\u2019 then the number of padding bits added are</p>",
      "OPT1": "<em>n</em> \u2013 1",
      "OPT2": "<em>n</em>",
      "OPT3": "<em>n</em> + 1",
      "OPT4": "None of these",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "fhPK/WKkcuYMengj9uY6cg==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "fhPK/WKkcuYMengj9uY6cg==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.33",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu17": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>The number of padding bits added to received codeword in CRC if generator is <em>x<sup>n</sup></em> + 1 is</p>",
      "OPT1": "<em>n</em> \u2013 1",
      "OPT2": "<em>n</em>",
      "OPT3": "0",
      "OPT4": "<em>n</em> + 1",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "9m/iwvJKC6coEJr5HJJczQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "9m/iwvJKC6coEJr5HJJczQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.33",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "TEST_NAME": "Topicwise Test-17 Part Syllabus GATE 2026 CS Computer Networks-1",
  "TEST_ID_ENCODED": "NjQ2NTQwNg==",
  "TEST_ID": "NjQ2NTQwNg=="
}